The next operator, identity, determines if two
variables share the same memory location. We will
cover this operator type and its purpose in more
detail later in this domain, but for this example,
look at some teams assigned to a game with their
color and ranks. In this 135-identity file,
Team 2, on line 2, has been made to be a
clone of Team 1, on line 1. Team 3, on line 3,
has the same specs as Team 1. But is Team 3 the
same as Team 1? The is keyword is used to identify
whether two variables share the same memory space.
On lines 5 and 6, we have two print statements,
one to see whether team 1 and team 2 share the
same memory space and one to see whether team
1 and team 3 share the same memory space. Do you
have any guesses as to what we will see when we
run this code? The first statement is True because
team 2 has been made equal to team 1. Thus,
the two variables share the same memory
space. But, team 3, even though it looks
to be the same as team 1, is technically
a new variable with its own set of values,
so it does not share the same memory space as
team 1. Later, we will see why this is important,
but because we are focused on the sequence
of operator types compared to one another,
know that identity happens before logical and
assignment but after arithmetic and comparison.
The importance of identity in this context is
that if two variables share the same memory space,
they will have equal values, and thus,
a developer can decide which variable to
change later in code, if necessary,
to help fulfill the goal of an app.